THOMAS BONNIN

Seeblickstrasse 24, 8038 Zurich thomas.bonnin@gmail.com +41 77 500 21 67 www.thomasbonnin.com

Permit B

Software engineer with 14+ years of experience, I have developed products used successfully by millions of people around the world. I value simplicity and good user-experience. I have specialised in server-side technologies with a preference for functional programming and static programming languages. I enjoy making a difference and learning everyday about software craftsmanship. I am interested in a role where my experience in software and infrastructure would add value.

WORK HISTORY

Principal Software Engineer Tamedia

May 2020 - Nov 2021 Zurich, Switzerland

Senior member of the Tamedia Paidmedia technology team

- Design the new Tamedia digital architecture and how the different systems (paywall, accounts, webshop, back office, ...) integrate with each other
- Implement data flows between all internal and 3rd-party systems (Kafka, Java, Kubernetes)
- Built Tamedia business analytics and data lake infrastructure (AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, dbt, SQL, python)
- Responsible for the support and training of analysts in their usage of the data lake to provide insights about our customers and our business

Software Engineer Guardian News & Media

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019

London, UK

Senior member of the data technology team

- Built and improved The Guardian data pipelines (Scala, Spark, AWS, BigQuery, dbt) allowing analysts, engineering teams and other departments to collect and turn data into actions
- · Led the effort to ensure data collection, retention and accesses are compliant with regulations
- Mentored developers (functional programming, importance of testing, value of post-mortems...)
- Encouraged engineering best practices
- Contributed to open-source project (Scanamo)

Software Engineer Guardian News & Media

Jan 2016 - Jan 2018 London, UK

Senior member of the "dotcom" team:

- · Led server-side development and infrastructure of the website (Scala, Play, AWS, Fastly)
- Ensured The Guardian website stays fast and reliable
- · Improved developer experience and deployment pipeline
- Promoted engineering best practices and mentored other developers

Software Engineer (iOS) Etsy

August 2014 - August 2015 New York, NY

Member of the App Core team:

- Accountable for code components shared by all Etsy iOS apps (logging, networking, i18n, ...)
- Led performance tracking (e.g. Graphite client) and speed improvements (e.g. Cold startup time)
- Improved Continuous Integration process in partnership with the Test & Automation team

Chief Software Architect

June 2013 - July 2014

Livestream

New York, NY

Reported to the CEO and accountable for the platform and engineering teams (Website, API, Mobile):

- Led the planning and execution of all platform technical projects
- Accountable for the management, development and recruitment of engineers in NYC

Head of Mobile apps

May 2012 - May 2013

Livestream

New York, NY

Leader of the Livestream mobile team (6 people)

Software Engineer

Feb 2010 - Mar 2012

Producteev (Task Management software)

New York, NY

Created Producteev iOS and Mac apps, improved and maintained Producteev public API (PHP)

Freelance Software Engineer (iOS)

Jan 2009 - Feb 2010

Self-employed

Paris, France

Software Engineer (Java, .Net, web)

Jun 2007 - Dec 2008

Sagem Avionics, Inc

Dallas, TX

EDUCATION

Master Degree

2004 - 2007

IUP MIAGE (Five year degree in Computer Science and Management)

Toulouse / Montreal

Bachelor Degree

2002 - 2004

DUT Informatique (Two year college degree in Computer Science)

Rodez, France

LANGUAGES

Bilingual English/French, Beginner German

INTERESTS

Running (long distance, trail running), chess, cooking, violin, travelling